ROSHNA VAKKEEL Junior Full Stack Software Developer

<u>vakkeel.roshna@gmail.com</u> • +0049 17680599495 • Berlin <u>LinkedIn</u> • <u>GitHub</u> • <u>Portfolio</u>

Executive Summary

I am a passionate Junior Software Developer with a Diploma in Full stack Software Development and Bioorganic Chemist with 10+ years of research and interdisciplinary project management experience. Possessing transferable skills such as effective communication, interpersonal skills, team-work, diligence, composure and patience, I aspire to be a bridge between Science and Tech. Now, I am eager to gain entry into the tech industry into an exciting development team where I can develop and contribute my unique creative, problem-solving, interpersonal and critical thinking skills.

Education

Sep 2022–Mar 2023 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Specialization: Advanced Frontend

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland (Credit: University of West of Scotland)

Aug 2007–Apr 2014 Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) in Chemistry

National Chemical Laboratory (NCL), Pune, India

Aug 2005–Jun 2007 Masters of Science (MSc) in Organic Chemistry

University of Pune, India

Aug 2002–Jun 2005 Bachelors of Science (BSc) in Chemistry

Abeda Inamdar College, University of Pune, India

Technical Skillset

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python

Libraries/Frameworks: React, Django, Bootstrap, React-Bootstrap, Django-REST, Pandas

Database Technology: Postgres-SQL

Communication Protocols: APIs, REST, HTTP, JSON (Data Format)

Development Workflow: Git (Version control), GitHub (Hosting), VSCode (IDE , Editing),

Heroku (PaaS, to deploy and manage apps), Markdown (READMe texts)

App Development Platforms: Mendix (SaaS, low-code platform to develop mobile/web apps)

(MENDIX Rapid Developer Certification, No. 37687 – 3rd July 2022)

Web Design Tools: Chrome DevTools, Lighthouse, Balsamiq, Lucidchart

Portfolio projects

Be Inspired - A social media App to connect people to spread positivity through their inspirations.
 Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS with React-Bootstrap, JavaScript, React (Front End) and, Python,
 Django-REST framework (Back End) along with Heroku for hosting website.

GitHub: https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/be-inspired-pp5-ci

- Little Learner's Lab Logs A website for kids to explore and create activity logs of fun experiments.
 Technologies Used HTML5, CSS with Bootstrap, Python, Django framework, Postgres-SQL DB, Cloudinary for media management, Heroku for hosting website.
 - GitHub: https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/Little Learners Lab Logs
- myLab Data Manager A lab chemical inventory parsing and searching software.

Technologies Used - Python, Pandas Library and Heroku for hosting website.

GitHub: https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/myLab_Data_Manager

• Chem Meets Codes – Computational chem evolution vs programming languages – A comaprison. Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS3.

GitHub: https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/Chem_Meets_Codes

• Chem Around Us – A guiz based on chemistry that surrounds us.

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript.

GitHub: https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/Chem_Around_Us

Work and Research Experience

Jul 2014-Nov 2018

Post-doctoral Research Associate

Max-Planck Institute for Polymer Chemistry, Mainz, Germany & INM – Leibniz Institute for New Materials, Saarbrücken, Germany.

- Gained technical expertise on experimentation, analysis, data collection and further studies. Maintained safety data sheets for chemicals, synthesized compounds etc., and GMP guidelines.
- Supervised and trained PhD, project students and CTAs.
- Preparation of budget proposals for projects, procurement of material and management of inventory
- Collaborate and co-ordinate meetings with cross-functional experts from various scientific disciplines
- Prepare SDS, SOPs for laboratory instruments, and follow good laboratory practices
- Writing, editing, and proofreading scientific manuscripts following scientific writing guidelines
- Handle scientific structure elucidation software ChemDraw, PyMOL, MERCURY (crystal structure), Molecular modelling techniques Schrödinger software.
- Presented in several national and international conferences 12 poster and 5 oral presentations.
- Published manuscripts in high impact journals 13 publications in WILEY-VCH, ACS, RSC, journals with a total of over 490 citations, including *Nature* (IF: 49.96). As Author Name: Roshna V. Nair. https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=uJ58rfgAAAAJ&hl=en

Voluntary Activities

- **Guest Editor, Gels, MDPI** (*Nov 2021–Present*) Special Issue (SI) on "Functional Hydrogels for Biomedical Applications" (https://www.mdpi.com/journal/gels/special issues/functional hydrogels biomedical)
- Reviewer Journal of Food and Drug Analysis (Sciencedirect), Nutrition (Elsevier) since 2015

Additional Information

- English (Native), German (Intermediate), Hindi (Native), Malayalam (Native)
- Career Gap: Nov 2018 Nov 2021: Motherhood, German course and Pandemic.
- Special Interests: Music, learning languages, Yoga, travelling, intercultural events
- Enrolled in EdX's CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript and creating new Apps.